<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Intersight Service for HashiCorp Terraform on Infrastructure as Code Lab</title><link>https://wookie-labs.github.io/iac-workshop-intersight/ist/</link><description>Recent content in Intersight Service for HashiCorp Terraform on Infrastructure as Code Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 14:11:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wookie-labs.github.io/iac-workshop-intersight/ist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>IST Setup</title><link>https://wookie-labs.github.io/iac-workshop-intersight/ist/setup_ist/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 13:42:13 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://wookie-labs.github.io/iac-workshop-intersight/ist/setup_ist/</guid><description>In the previous sections of this lab you have managed Intersight related configuration via the Intersight terraform provider. The transition from Terraform open source (OSS) to Terraform Cloud was incredibly simple due to Intersight being a SaaS based service and therefore the API is securely publicly accessible.
What happens when you want the operational benefits of Terraform Cloud but need to manage on-premises infrastructure? As discussed in the Terraform Primer Challenges with On-premise section of this guide, IST addresses this challenge by leveraging the Intersight Assist framework to deploy and lifecycle manage Terraform Cloud Agents enabling secure access from Terraform Cloud to private infrastructure as shown in the figure below:</description></item><item><title>Agent Pools</title><link>https://wookie-labs.github.io/iac-workshop-intersight/ist/using_agents/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 09:17:16 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://wookie-labs.github.io/iac-workshop-intersight/ist/using_agents/</guid><description>Now that IST has provisioned an Agent pool within your Terraform Cloud organization, you can configure your existing workspace to leverage the agent pool to manage an on-premise vCenter instance. In this section you will deploy two new virtual machines using a module within the Private Module Registry of the Wookie-Labs Terraform Cloud organization.
Using the Agent Pool Once an agent pools is created within a TFC organization, the pool can be configured for use at the Workspace level.</description></item><item><title>Deploy VMs</title><link>https://wookie-labs.github.io/iac-workshop-intersight/ist/deploy_vms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 14:08:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://wookie-labs.github.io/iac-workshop-intersight/ist/deploy_vms/</guid><description>In the GitHub + Terraform Cloud Use Community Modules section you used a community contributed module publicly available on the Terraform Registry to simplify the management of various Intersight related policy. In this section you will similarly use a module however this time from the private registry hosted within your Terraform Cloud organization.
Consumers of Terraform would typically use a private registry vs the public registry when they have modules that can&amp;rsquo;t, shouldn&amp;rsquo;t, or don&amp;rsquo;t need to be public.</description></item></channel></rss>